<doc t='O' id='329262-2009'>
    <CONTRACT ctype='S' lgorig='en' lg='en' category='orig' hd='3340'>
        <refdtd>CONTRACT</refdtd>
        <refojs>
            <colloj>S</colloj>
            <nooj>229</nooj>
            <datepub>20091127</datepub>
            <lgoj>EN</lgoj>
        </refojs>
        <codifdata>
            <sector code='N'>National or federal Agency/Office</sector>
            <natnotice code='3'>Contract notice</natnotice>
            <market code='4'>Service contract</market>
            <proc code='4'>Negotiated procedure</proc>
            <marketorg code='B'>European Economic Area (EEA), with participation by GPA countries</marketorg>
            <typebid code='1'>Global tender</typebid>
            <awardcrit code='2'>The most economic tender</awardcrit>
            <originalcpv code='72230000'>Custom software development services</originalcpv>
            <originalcpv code='72267100'>Maintenance of information technology software</originalcpv>
            <datedisp>20091126</datedisp>
            <daterec>20091126</daterec>
            <refnotice>2009/S 112-161942</refnotice>
            <deadlinereq>20100114</deadlinereq>
            <deadlinerec>20100115 12:00</deadlinerec>
            <isocountry>NO</isocountry>
            <mainactivities code='S'>General public/services</mainactivities>
            <nodocojs>329262-2009</nodocojs>
        </codifdata>
        <tidoc>
            <p>NO-Oslo: custom software development services</p>
            <p>2009/S 229-329262</p>
        </tidoc>
        <stidoc>
            <p>CONTRACT NOTICE</p>
        </stidoc>
        <stidoc>
            <p>Services</p>
        </stidoc>
        <contents>
            <grseq>
                <tigrseq>SECTION I: CONTRACTING AUTHORITY</tigrseq>
                <marklist sep=''>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>I.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>NAME, ADDRESSES AND CONTACT POINT(S):</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>
                                <addr><organisation>NAV Drift og utvikling</organisation>, <address>Sannergata 2,
                                    Postboks 5200 Nydalen</address>, Contact: <contact>Anskaffelse og økonomi</contact>,
                                    Attn: <attention>Gunnar Helge Wiik</attention>, <countrycode>N</countrycode>-<postalcode>
                                        0426
                                    </postalcode>
                                    <town>Oslo</town>. Tel. <tel>+47 21071000</tel>. E-mail:
                                    <email>
                                        <txemail>gunnar.helge.wiik@nav.no</txemail>
                                    </email>
                                    . Fax <fax>+47 21071010</fax>.
                                </addr>
                            </p>
                            <p><ft type='bold'>Internet address(es)</ft>:
                            </p>
                            <p>General address of the contracting authority: <txurl>www.nav.no</txurl>.
                            </p>
                            <p>Address of the buyer profile: <txurl>
                                http://www.doffin.no/search/Search_AuthProfile.aspx?ID=AA0005</txurl>.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <ft type='bold'>Further information can be obtained at:</ft>
                                As in above-mentioned contact point(s).
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <ft type='bold'>Specifications and additional documents (including documents for
                                    competitive dialogue and a dynamic purchasing system) can be obtained at:
                                </ft>
                                As in above-mentioned contact point(s).
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <ft type='bold'>Tenders or requests to participate must be sent to:</ft>
                                As in above-mentioned contact point(s).
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>I.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>TYPE OF THE CONTRACTING AUTHORITY AND MAIN ACTIVITY OR ACTIVITIES:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>National or federal agency/office.</p>
                            <p>General public services.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                </marklist>
            </grseq>
            <grseq>
                <tigrseq>SECTION II: OBJECT OF THE CONTRACT</tigrseq>
                <marklist sep=''>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>DESCRIPTION</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Title attributed to the contract by the contracting authority:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Procurement of maintenance and development agreement for Financial systems V2.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Type of contract and location of works, place of delivery or of performance:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Services.</p>
                            <p>Service category: No 7.</p>
                            <p>Main place of performance: Oslo, Norway.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>The notice involves:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>The establishment of a framework agreement.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.4)</nomark>
                        <timark>Information on framework agreement:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Framework agreement with a single operator.</p>
                            <p>Duration of the framework agreement: Duration in year(s): 4.</p>
                            <p>Justification for a framework agreement, the duration of which exceeds four years: It is
                                a considerable investment for a new administrative service provider to develop the
                                necessary functional and technical competence which is specialised for the system which
                                shall be administered.
                            </p>
                            <p>The amount will normally be several man labour years for up to 2 years. In addition a new
                                administrative service provider must establish routines and processes in accordance with
                                the contract requirements and the customer's use of the framework and system must be
                                understood and anchored. If these costs cannot be divided over a sufficiently long
                                contract period, it will be difficult for others than the established service provider
                                to win an administration contract.
                            </p>
                            <p>In order to ensure access to competence in order to get a new administrative service
                                provider, NAV will ensure access to competence for assistance for the new administrative
                                service provider for a period of 2 years. Such transition contracts also help to ensure
                                a real competition for the administrative contracts.
                            </p>
                            <p>These are very comprehensive contracts, and service providers must make considerable
                                investments, which can be said to have a depreciation period over the whole of the
                                contract period of 4+1+1 years, in order to fulfil the contracts. A contract period of
                                4+1+1 years has been chosen in order to ensure competition.
                            </p>
                            <p>Estimated total value of purchases for the entire duration of the framework agreement:
                            </p>
                            <p>Estimated value excluding VAT:</p>
                            <p>Range: between 150 000 000 and 210 000 000 NOK.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.5)</nomark>
                        <timark>Short description of the contract or purchase(s):</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>The aim is to enter into a maintenance contract and framework agreement for further
                                development with one service provider of services connected to Financial systems.
                            </p>
                            <p>Requirements regarding workplace will be given in the tender documents. The Awarding
                                Authority finds it necessary to provide guidelines for this area as early as in the
                                qualification documents. The object for these guidelines is close cooperation between
                                the Awarding Authority and supplier.
                            </p>
                            <p>— Norwegian language is required in connection with all communication with the Awarding
                                Authority. This involves both reports, meetings, documentation, user support and
                                additional information. The system documentation may, if agreed upon, be prepared in
                                English.
                            </p>
                            <p>The maintenance services shall basically be implemented in the Awarding Authority’s
                                premises.
                            </p>
                            <p>Further development shall basically be implemented in the Awarding Authority’s premises
                                unless the parties have agreed differently.
                            </p>
                            <p>The annual value of the agreement will vary, but the extent is expected to be from 10 000
                                000 to 20 000 000 NOK per annum.
                            </p>
                            <p>The agreement shall be for 4 years, starting from contract signing. Option for the
                                Awarding Authority to prolong the agreement with further 1+1 year(s).
                            </p>
                            <p>Note: To register your interest in this notice and obtain any additional information
                                please visit the Doffin Web Site at <txurl>
                                    http://www.doffin.no/Search/Search_Switch.aspx?ID=192305</txurl>.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.6)</nomark>
                        <timark>Common procurement vocabulary (CPV):</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p><txcpv txt='Custom software development services'>72230000</txcpv>, <txcpv
                                    txt='Maintenance of information technology software'>72267100</txcpv>.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.7)</nomark>
                        <timark>Contract covered by the Government Procurement Agreement (GPA):</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Yes.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.1.8)</nomark>
                        <timark>Division into lots:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>No.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>II.1.9)</nomark>
                        <timark>Variants will be accepted:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>QUANTITY OR SCOPE OF THE CONTRACT</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.2.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Total quantity or scope:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>The annual value of the contract will vary, but the amount is estimated to normally lie
                                within 25 000 000 to 35 000 000 NOK per annum.
                            </p>
                            <p>Estimated value excluding VAT:</p>
                            <p>Range: between 150 000 000 and 210 000 000 NOK.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>II.2.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Options:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Yes.</p>
                            <p>Description of these options: The contract will be for 4 years from when it is signed.
                                The awarding authority (the customer) will have an option for an extension of the
                                contract for a further 1+1 year.
                            </p>
                            <p>Number of possible renewals: 2.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>II.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>DURATION OF THE CONTRACT OR TIME-LIMIT FOR COMPLETION:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                </marklist>
            </grseq>
            <grseq>
                <tigrseq>SECTION III: LEGAL, ECONOMIC, FINANCIAL AND TECHNICAL INFORMATION</tigrseq>
                <marklist sep=''>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>CONDITIONS RELATING TO THE CONTRACT</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.1.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Deposits and guarantees required:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.1.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Main financing conditions and payment arrangements and/or reference to the relevant
                            provisions regulating them:
                        </timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.1.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>Legal form to be taken by the group of economic operators to whom the contract is to be
                            awarded:
                        </timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.1.4)</nomark>
                        <timark>Other particular conditions to which the performance of the contract is subject:
                        </timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>No.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>CONDITIONS FOR PARTICIPATION</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.2.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Personal situation of economic operators, including requirements relating to enrolment
                            on professional or trade registers:
                        </timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Information and formalities necessary for evaluating if requirements are met: Value added
                                tax certificate (National requirement).
                            </p>
                            <p>Company tax certificate (National requirement).</p>
                            <p>Self-declaration in compliance with Appendix 2 (HSE) of the Norwegian procurement
                                regulations (National requirement).
                            </p>
                            <p>Other documentation required:</p>
                            <p>— Evidence of enrolment on the professional or trade register, as required by national
                                law, in the country where the company is established, for instance company certificate
                                from the Brønnøysund Register Centre.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.2.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Economic and financial capacity:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Information and formalities necessary for evaluating if requirements are met: Statement
                                of the company’s turnover, of relevance to this contract, for previous years.
                            </p>
                            <p>Other documentation required:</p>
                            <p>— The company’s annual reports to the Brønnøysund Register Centre with the auditor’s
                                report for the most resent years, as well as newer information with relevance to the
                                company’s accounting figures,
                            </p>
                            <p>— The company’s most resent annual accounts with notes.</p>
                            <p>Minimum level(s) of standards possibly required: It is required that the supplier has
                                good financial solidity.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>III.2.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>Technical capacity:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Information and formalities necessary for evaluating if requirements are met:</p>
                            <p>Other documentation required:</p>
                            <p>— Experience,</p>
                            <p>— Description of the service provider's 3 principal relevant contracts for the last 3
                                years including values, roles/responsibility areas, technology, dates, activity
                                areas/activity processes and recipients. The service provider is asked to include one or
                                several deliveries which include use of flexible methodology. Names and contact
                                information of the contact person shall be given so that the Awarding Authority can
                                address the person, if required.
                            </p>
                            <p>— Implementation ability.</p>
                            <p>— Description of the provider’s technical capacity and professional qualifications. The
                                relevant capacity shall be a description of relevant units in the Awarding Authority’s
                                organisation. The relevant qualifications shall be a brief overview of general, relevant
                                competence in the provider’s organisation. Information of available personnel and CV's
                                shall not be given,
                            </p>
                            <p>— Use of sub suppliers, see the qualification documents point 3.5.</p>
                            <p>— Methods for quality assurance.</p>
                            <p>— A description of methods and processes which are relevant for ensuring quality of the
                                delivery. The subjects in the quality document’s points 2.2.3.2, 2.3.3.2, 2.4.3.2,
                                2.5.3.2 and 2.6 should be covered in the description,
                            </p>
                            <p>— An account of the company's quality assurance system/control system as well as any
                                certificates issued by independent bodies.
                            </p>
                            <p>Minimum level(s) of standards possibly required:</p>
                            <p>— Relevant experience from similar assignments is required,</p>
                            <p>— A very good ability to fulfil the contract is required,</p>
                            <p>— Established and suitable methods for quality assurance are required.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.2.4)</nomark>
                        <timark>Reserved contracts:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>CONDITIONS SPECIFIC TO SERVICES CONTRACTS</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.3.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Execution of the service is reserved to a particular profession:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>III.3.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Legal entities should indicate the names and professional qualifications of the staff
                            responsible for the execution of the service:
                        </timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                </marklist>
            </grseq>
            <grseq>
                <tigrseq>SECTION IV: PROCEDURE</tigrseq>
                <marklist sep=''>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>TYPE OF PROCEDURE</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.1.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Type of procedure:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Negotiated.</p>
                            <p>Candidates have already been selected: no.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.1.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Limitations on the number of operators who will be invited to tender or to
                            participate:
                        </timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Envisaged minimum number: 3. Maximum number: 5</p>
                            <p>Objective criteria for choosing the limited number of candidates: The selection of
                                providers will be made amongst the service providers who fulfil the requirements for
                                participation in the competition.
                            </p>
                            <p>The selection will be based on the degree that the qualification requirements listed in
                                the qualification documents point 3.4 are fulfilled. The following weighting will be
                                used in the selection:
                            </p>
                            <p>Qualification requirements: Experience.</p>
                            <p>Weighting: 35 %.</p>
                            <p>Qualification requirements: Implementation ability (the Awarding Authority will evaluate
                                capacity and not competence/qualifications in relation to selection of providers).
                                Weighting: 35 %.
                            </p>
                            <p>Qualification requirements: Methods for quality assurance.</p>
                            <p>Weighting: 30 %.</p>
                            <p>The assessment of the suppliers will be implemented as follows: The provider will be
                                awarded one grade for each qualification requirement on a scale from 0 to 10 where 10 is
                                the highest grade. Each of these grades will be multiplied with the prevailing
                                weighting.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.1.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>Reduction of the number of operators during the negotiation or dialogue:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Recourse to staged procedure to gradually reduce the number of solutions to be discussed
                                or tenders to be negotiated yes.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>AWARD CRITERIA</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.2.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Award criteria:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>The most economically advantageous tender in terms of the criteria stated in the
                                specifications, in the invitation to tender or to negotiate or in the descriptive
                                document.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.2.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>An electronic auction will be used:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>No.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>IV.3.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>File reference number attributed by the contracting authority:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Previous publication(s) concerning the same contract:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>
                                <ft type='bold'>Prior information notice</ft>
                            </p>
                            <p>Notice number in OJ: <txnum ref='161942-2009'>2009/S 112-161942</txnum> of 11.6.2009.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>Conditions for obtaining specifications and additional documents or descriptive
                            document:
                        </timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Time limit for receipt of requests for documents or for accessing documents: 14.1.2010.
                            </p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3.4)</nomark>
                        <timark>Time-limit for receipt of tenders or requests to participate:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>15.1.2010 - 12:00.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3.5)</nomark>
                        <timark>Date of dispatch of invitations to tender or to participate to selected candidates:
                        </timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>5.5.2010.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>IV.3.6)</nomark>
                        <timark>Language(s) in which tenders or requests to participate may be drawn up:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>Other: Norwegian.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>IV.3.7)</nomark>
                        <timark>Minimum time frame during which the tenderer must maintain the tender:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>IV.3.8)</nomark>
                        <timark>Conditions for opening tenders:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                </marklist>
            </grseq>
            <grseq>
                <tigrseq>SECTION VI: COMPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</tigrseq>
                <marklist sep=''>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>THIS IS A RECURRENT PROCUREMENT:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>CONTRACT RELATED TO A PROJECT AND/OR PROGRAMME FINANCED BY EU FUNDS:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>VI.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>(NT Ref:192448).</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.4)</nomark>
                        <timark>PROCEDURES FOR APPEAL</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.4.1)</nomark>
                        <timark>Body responsible for appeal procedures:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.4.2)</nomark>
                        <timark>Lodging of appeals:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur tbo='yes'>
                        <nomark>VI.4.3)</nomark>
                        <timark>Service from which information about the lodging of appeals may be obtained:</timark>
                    </mlioccur>
                    <mlioccur>
                        <nomark>VI.5)</nomark>
                        <timark>DATE OF DISPATCH OF THIS NOTICE:</timark>
                        <txtmark>
                            <p>26.11.2009.</p>
                        </txtmark>
                    </mlioccur>
                </marklist>
            </grseq>
        </contents>
    </CONTRACT>
</doc>